VALON RAMA FULLSTACK WEB DEVELOPER

VRAMA21@GMAIL.COM

PHILADELPHIA, PA

609.204.3407

2

VRAMA21

C

VRAMA21



VRAMA21.GITHUB.IO/PORTFOLIO

TECHNOLOGIES

Languages

Python, Javascript

Frontend

ReactJS, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Jinja

Backend

Django, Flask, Express, NodeJS, REST API

Databases

MySQL, MongoDB, Postgres, SQLite

Other

Git, jQuery, JSON, Microsoft Suite, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Illustrator

PROJECTS

Sheriff Sale

Sheriff Sale is a real-estate data aggregator pertaining to sheriff sale auctions in New Jersey. It scrapes upcoming auction data and fetches associated data pertaining to each listing from external sources, such as Trulia and Zillow.

Python, Flask, SQLite, Jinja

LetsPlayHockey

LetsPlayHockey is a resource for hockey players to find, create, and sign-up for local pick-up hockey games. Search players by their skill level, position, and/or their availability.

Javascript, Express, MySQL, React

Flex Point-of-Sale

Flex Point-of-Sale is a restaurant point-of-sale application. The goal of this application is to bring in newer modern technologies to a category which has been out-of-date and lacked any recent innovations, flexbility to handle any test-case in the restaurant industry, and to increase work productivity and reduce potential errors.

Python, Django, Postgres, React

WORK EXPERIENCE

06/2016 - Present | Atlantic City, NJ

Manager/Supervisor | Marco Polo's Inc.

- Managed a business grossing over \$1 million a year.
- Managed inventory and stock bi-weekly.
- · Recruited, hired, and oversaw training of staff.
- Supervised all floor activity to maintain high standards of customer satisfaction.
- Shifted business strategies resulting in increases of 15% in sales and 11% in profits each year.
- Integrated, maintained, and upgraded Point-of-Sale software systems, producing higher efficiency and accuracy on delivering products.

09/2013 - 04/2014 | Philadelphia, PA

Software Quality Assurance Intern National Board of Medical Examiners

- · Constructed and executed test cases for web applications based on design specifications and requirements.
- Detected and documented software bugs and potential failure points.
- · Collaborated with developers, business analysts, and project managers to maintain the project timeline and deliverable.
- Ensured applications are fully functional, stable, and bug-free prior to deployment.

EDUCATION

2019 - 2020

UPenn LPS Coding Bootcamp

Fullstack Web Development

Drexel University
Computer Engineering